<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<tryton>
    <data skiptest="1" noupdate="1">
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_1">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Combined oral contraception</field>
            <field name="description">Contraceptive methods that consist of taking a daily tablet that contains two hormones, progestogen and estrogen.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_2">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Combined injectable contraception</field>
            <field name="description">Contraceptive methods that consist of the administration of a monthly injection that contains two hormones, progestogen and estrogen.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_3">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Transdermal contraception</field>
            <field name="description">Contraceptive methods that consist in the administration of a patch that contains two hormones: progestogen and estrogen.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_4">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Progestin-only oral contraception</field>
            <field name="description">Contraceptive method consisting of taking a daily tablet containing a single hormone: progestogen:
 - Levonorgestrel
- Desogestrel
- Linestrenol
They are also called minipill</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_5">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Injectable contraception based on progestin alone.</field>
            <field name="description">Contraceptive method consisting of intramuscular gluteal or deltoid injection of a quarterly vial containing a progestogen deposit: Medroxyprogesterone acetate 150 mg.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_6">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Subdermal implants</field>
            <field name="description">Contraceptive methods consisting of the subdermal placement of 1, 2 or 6 cartridges or non-biodegradable plastic cylindrical capsules containing a progestogen deposit: etonorgestrel (ENG) or levonorgestrel (LNG) that is progressively released for 3 to 5 years respectively, which is its time of use.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_7">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Emergency contraception</field>
            <field name="description">Emergency contraceptive method that women can use within 5 days after a sexual intercourse without contraceptive protection in order to avoid an unplanned pregnancy. It should be used exclusively as an emergency method and not as a regular form of contraception. Emergency contraception is approved by the World Health Organization (WHO), the International Family Planning Federation (IPPF) and the Food and Drug Administration (FDA).</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_8">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Copper intrauterine device (IUD)</field>
            <field name="description">It is a contraceptive made of T-shaped polyethylene, with 2 flexible horizontal arms. It has around it copper wire with a surface of 380 mm2. It is inserted vaginally through the cervix and placed at the level of the fundus of the uterus. This procedure must be done by a qualified provider.
It has 2 polyethylene guide wires that remain at the level of the vagina for control and extraction. Its use can be for 10 years.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_9">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Levonorgestrel-releasing intrauterine device (IUD-LNG)</field>
            <field name="description">Contraceptive method of polyethylene in the form of T, with the ability to continuously release a hormonal component (levonorgestrel 20ug / day). As in the Cu-IUD, two wires are attached to the end that is close to the external cervical os. Its use can be for 5 years.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_10">
            <field name="gender">male</field>
            <field name="name">Male condom</field>
            <field name="description">Barrier method that prevents contact between semen and vaginal mucosa. The only method that also protects against sexually transmitted infections. Another technical name can be a condom. Cover or cover of latex that is placed on the erect penis of man.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_11">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Breastfeeding method (MELA</field>
            <field name="description">It is a temporary family planning method, based on exclusive breastfeeding in which the woman must comply with 3 conditions:
- Breastfeeding at free demand, day and night, without the use of formulas or breast milk substitutes
- Amenorrhea
- Newborn under 6 months</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_12">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Fertile female period (rhythm)</field>
            <field name="description">To determine the female fertile period there are 2 methods:
- Use of the calendar, determine the fertile days based on the menstrual cycle.
- Use of the signs and symptoms of the fertile period, such as: cervical mucus and basal body temperature (CB T)</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_13">
            <field name="gender">female</field>
            <field name="name">Tubal ligation salpingoclasm, or salpingoligadura</field>
            <field name="description">Surgical intervention in which female surgical contraception is performed through the section, cut and bilateral ligature of the fallopian tubes. It can be done postpartum, transcesarean or in the intergenesic interval.</field>
        </record>
        <record model="galeno.contraceptive.method" id="contraceptive_14">
            <field name="gender">male</field>
            <field name="name">Vasectomy</field>
            <field name="description">Surgical intervention in which male surgical contraception is performed by sectioning, cutting and bilateral ligation of the vas deferens.</field>
        </record>
    </data>
</tryton>
